redlion.net 2017-12-20

# Privacy and Cookies Policy | Red Lion

This Privacy and Cookies Policy applies to Red Lion Controls, Inc., as part of the group company Spectris Plc and discloses the privacy practices for [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/). If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please email us at [webmaster@redlion.net](mailto:webmaster@redlion.net).

**We respect your privacy**  
At Red Lion Controls we value our customers and their privacy. All personal information is used by our staff and authorized distributors to help customers fulfill their needs, ensuring efficiency in processing your orders. Personal information is information about identifiable individuals as defined by applicable law. Red Lion never sells, loans or rents out any personal information to any third party unless we are legally required to do so or with your written authorization. We may share your personal information with:

  1. Spectris Group companies or non-Spectris companies that provide services to Spectris companies and certain other third parties, but only where they offer adequate protection for your information and, in certain cases, only where you have provided your consent.
  2. In some cases, this may involve transferring your personal information to other countries (including the U.K., the U.S., Canada and other countries inside and outside the European Economic Area) where Spectris or non-Spectris companies or other third parties operate and process your personal information.

Precautions are taken to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. We use the industry-standard security protocol Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to encode sensitive information, such as credit card numbers for online purchase transactions, that passes between you and [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/). We employ the latest 128-bit encryption technology in all areas of the site, which require you to provide personal or account information. This means that the credit card information you send is encrypted by your computer, and then decrypted again on our side, preventing others from accessing your private information in between. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

**Unsubscribe**  
At your request and where the law requires us to do so, if you contact us using the unsubscribe link provided in the body of every Red Lion promotional emails we will ensure you only receive email regarding your recent orders and conformation when you have completed forms. Red Lion is the sole collector of information, and does not share your personal information for marketing purposes with any third parties without your written consent.

**More Privacy Terms...**  
Red Lion has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to our customers’ privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/) website. Any changes or updates to our privacy practices will be updated on this page of our website which is accessible from the footer of all website pages. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users either by email or physical mail.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses, browser type and time of day to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not use IP addresses to link to personally identifiable information.

**Registration**  
Various site forms require users to provide contact information (such as name and email address). This contact information is used to contact visitors upon request or in instances pertaining to order processing that may relate to credit card verification, product availability, shipping speed and more. Users can change contact preferences at any time by visiting [www.redlion.net/subscribe](http://www.redlion.net/subscribe). Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services.

**Cookies**  
This Cookie Policy applies to any websites, branded pages on third-party platforms (such as Facebook or YouTube), applications accessed or used through such websites or third-party plugins or sites that operate on behalf of Red Lion to distinguish you from other users of our website. This allows us to provide you with a better user experience when you browse our websites and helps us improve our sites.

By continuing to use Red Lion web properties, you are consenting to our use of cookies in accordance with this Cookie Policy. If you do not agree to our use of cookies in this way, you should set your browser settings accordingly or not use Red Lion web properties. If you disable the cookies that we use, this may impact your user experience while on [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/).

The table below summarizes the different types of cookie we use on [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/), together with their respective purpose and duration (i.e. how long each cookie will remain on your device).

Two types of cookies may be used on Red Lion web properties - "session cookies" and "persistent cookies". Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain on your device until you leave [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/). A persistent cookie remains on your device for much longer or until you manually delete it (how long the cookie remains on your device will depend on the duration or "lifetime" of the specific cookie and your browser settings).

### **Cookies used on** [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/)

**Type of Cookie**

| 

**What do they do?**

| 

**Do these cookies collect my personal data / identify me?**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Necessary

| 

Cookies that are essential to making [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/) work correctly. They enable visitors to move around our website and use our features. Examples include remembering previous actions (e.g. entered text) when  
navigating back to a page in the same session.

| 

These cookies do not identify you as an individual.

If you do not accept these cookies, it may affect the performance of our website.  
  
Performance

| 

Cookies that help us understand how visitors interact with our web properties by providing information about the areas visited, the time spent on the website and any issues encountered, such as error messages. They helps us improve the performance of our websites, alert of any concerns and more.

| 

These cookies don’t identify you as an individual. All data is collected and aggregated anonymously.  
  
Functionality

| 

Cookies that allow our web properties to remember the choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) to provide a more personalized online experience. They can also enable visitors to watch videos, play games and engage with social tools, such as blogs, chatrooms and forums.

| 

The information these cookies collect may include personally identifiable information that you have disclosed, such as your username or profile picture. We shall always be transparent with you about what information we collect, what we do with it and with whom we share it.

If you do not accept these cookies, it may affect website performance and functionality  and may restrict access to web content.  
  
Targeting / advertising

| 

Cookies that are used to deliver content that is more relevant to you and your interests. They may be used to deliver targeted advertising or to limit the number of times you see an advertisement. They also help us measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns on [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/).

We may use these cookies to remember websites you have visited and we may share this information with other parties, including advertisers and our agencies.

| 

Most types of these cookies track consumers via their [IP address](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/faqs/) so may collect some personal identifiable information.  
  
**What are cookies?**  
Cookies are files or pieces of information that may be stored on your computer (or other internet-enabled devices, such as a smartphone or tablet) when you visit a Red Lion web property. A cookie will usually contain the name of the website from which the cookie has come from, the "lifetime" of the cookie (i.e. how long it will remain on your device) and a value, which is usually a randomly generated unique number.

**What do we use cookies for?**  
We use cookies to make [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/) easier to use and to better tailor our web presence and products to your interests and needs. Cookies may also be used to help speed up your future activities and experience on our web properties. We also use cookies to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how people use our web properties and to help us improve web structure and content. We cannot identify you personally from this information.

**How can I control or delete cookies?**  
Most internet browsers are initially set up to automatically accept cookies. You can change the settings to block cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent to your device. There are a number of ways to manage cookies. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about how to adjust or modify your browser settings.

If you disable the cookies that we use, this may impact your experience while on [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/). For example, you may not be able to visit certain areas of the site.

If you use different devices to view and access [www.redlion.net](http://www.redlion.net/) (e.g. your computer, smartphone, tablet etc,), you will need to ensure that each browser on each device is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences. Click here for more information.

**FUNCTIONALITY**  
Social Media / Sharing:  
Allows you to share comments / ratings /pages / bookmarks and helps to provide access to social networks and social online tools more easily.

Third-Party Applications:  
Facebook Connect and Facebook plugins: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other>  
Linkedin: <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>  
Twitter: <https://twitter.com/privacy>  
Google Analytics : <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>   
YouTube Tracking: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

**Third-Party Plugins**  
When you visit a website that contains a social plugin, your browser establishes a direct link to third-party servers as opposed to through the Red Lion site. The content of the plugin is transferred by the third party directly to your browser, which embeds the latter into our website. Red Lion therefore has no influence over the scope of data that the third party collects using the plugin and you should refer to their individual policies for more details.

By utilizing these third-party plugins, you are informing these third-party companies that you have accessed the corresponding pages where the icon was placed. 

**Facebook Social Plugins**  
The Red Lion website uses Social Media Plugins provided by the social network facebook.com, which is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. The plugins can be recognized by the Facebook logo (white "f" on a blue tile or a "thumbs up" sign) or the notation "Facebook Social Plugin". The list and the look of Facebook Social Plugins can be viewed here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/page-plugin](mailto:https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/page-plugin).

Please refer to the Facebook data protection statement regarding the purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of data by Facebook, and the respective rights and settings options for protecting your privacy at <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>.  Please also contact Facebook directly with any questions regarding matters pertaining to their plugins.

If you are on Facebook and do not wish for Facebook to collect data about you via this website and link it to your member data already stored on Facebook, you must log out of Facebook before visiting this website, and any website that employs Facebook plugins. It is also possible to block Facebook Social Plugins by using add-ons for your browser.

**Google Analytics**  
The Red Lion website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc. which uses 'Cookies', text files stored on your computer, to allow an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there, according to Google.

If IP anonymization is activated on this website, within EU Member States or in other member states of the European Economic Area, Google will shorten your IP address before transmitting it. Only in exceptional cases will your full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. The IP anonymization is active on this website. On behalf of Red Lion Controls, Google will use this information to analyze your use of the website, compile reports on website activity and to provide other services to Red Lion in connection with website activity and Internet related services for internal record keeping within Red Lion itself.

The IP address provided from your browser under Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. You may prevent cookies from being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser or by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

**Google+**  
The Red Lion website uses the "+1" button for the social network Google Plus, which is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (hereafter referred to as "Google"). The button can be recognized by the "+1" on a white or colored background.

Please refer to the Google data protection statement on the "+1" button regarding the purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of data by Google, and the respective rights and settings options for protecting your privacy at: <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>

**Google Maps**  
The Red Lion website uses Google Maps on some pages to display interactive maps or to demonstrate directions. Google Maps is a map service from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California 94043, USA. By using Google Maps, information about the use of this website can be transferred to Google in the USA, including your IP address and the (starting) address you entered in the route planner.

If you visit a web page of our website that includes Google Maps, your browser directly connects to Google servers. The map will be transmitted from Google directly to your browser and then integrated into the website. We have no influence of the scope of data collected by Google in this way.

If you do not want Google to collect, process or use data about you from our website, you can deactivate JavaScript in your browser settings; however the map functionality will be disabled.

To learn more about how Google’s data collection, its further processing and the use of data, as well as your rights and your possibilities to configure your computer settings to secure your privacy, please visit Google privacy policies: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

**LinkedIn**  
The Red Lion website uses Social Plug-ins from the social network linkedin.com operated by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

**Marketo**  
The Red Lion website uses a marketing automation system provided by Marketo Inc., 901 Mariners Island Boulevard, Suite #500, San Mateo, CA 94404, USA.. For more information regarding Marketo’s specific cookies, please refer to the [Marketo Cookies Policy](http://legal.marketo.com/cookies/) and to [Marketo Privacy Policy](http://legal.marketo.com/privacy/).

**Twitter**  
The Red Lion website uses the Twitter service buttons which are operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. They can be identified by terminology such as "Twitter" or "sequence", combined with a stylized blue bird. For more information please refer to the Twitter data protection statement at <http://twitter.com/privacy>.

**YouTube**  
The Red Lion website uses the YouTube video platform operated by YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave. San Bruno, CA 94066 USA. YouTube is a platform that enables playback of audio and video files.

When you load a page on our website, the integrated YouTube player establishes a connection to YouTube in order to ensure the technical transmission of the video or audio file. When the connection to YouTube is established, data is transferred to YouTube.

For information about the scope and purpose of data collection, the further processing and use of the data by YouTube and your rights and the settings you can configure to protect your privacy, please refer to the [YouTube Data Protection Notice](mailto:https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines).

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact us at one of the addresses below. We will confirm on request what personal information we hold about you, update your information where appropriate, remove your information and/or correct any inaccuracies in such personal information. 

**Red Lion Headquarters** |   | **Red Lion Controls BV  
Europe Middle East Africa** |   | **Red Lion China**  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
20 Willow Springs Circle  
York PA 17406 USA  
+1 (717) 767-6511 phone  
+1 (717) 764-0839 fax  

|   | 

Softwareweg 9  
3821 BN Amersfoort, The Netherlands  
+31 (0) 33-4723-225 phone  
+31 (0) 33-4893-793 fax  

|   | 

Unit 1102, XinMao Plaza Building 9  
No. 99 Tianzhou Road  
Shanghai, P.R. China 200233  
+86 (21) 6113 3688 phone  
+86 (21) 6113 3683 fax  
  
**Responsible for content:    
​Mrs. Jennifer Bentzel** |   | **Responsible for content:  
Mrs. Esther Scheen** |   | **Responsible for content:    
​Mrs. Celine Zhang**  
  
**Chief executive: Mr. Jack Lee and Mr. Mike Evelhoch**  
Registration number: 32089022

USt.-Id-Nr.: NL81.032.3333.B01.
